<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: metasploit | 0x0badc0[.]de]]></title>
  <link href="http://flowztul.github.io/blog/categories/metasploit/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://flowztul.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-22T22:36:35+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://flowztul.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Lutz Wolf]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Per-User PostgreSQL Database for Metasploit]]></title>
    <link href="http://flowztul.github.io/blog/2014/01/22/per-user-postgresql-database-for-metasploit/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-22T22:02:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://flowztul.github.io/blog/2014/01/22/per-user-postgresql-database-for-metasploit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Database support in <a href="http://www.metasploit.com/">Metasploit</a> is really handy
for pentesting engangements that cover more than just a few hosts. With
database support, Metasploit</p>

<ul>
<li>lets you import Nmap and other scans into the database,</li>
<li>lets you search the database for hosts and services, which provides for a really handy way of populating <code>RHOSTS</code>, and</li>
<li>provides a credentials database that is automatically populated by most of the auxiliary login scanner modules. Some of the login scanner modules can also use the credentials database as a source for verifying known credentials against new services.</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="http://www.offensive-security.com/metasploit-unleashed/Using_the_Database">Metasploit Unleashed</a>
has some more information about the database, which should be enough to get you
started once you managed to set everything up. Getting PostgreSQL up and
running is fairly straightforward, and you can even get by without a fully
configured PostgreSQL installation, by running the database server from the
same user account that you use to run Metasploit. This was first shown to me by
one of my <a href="https://www.redteam-pentesting.de/redteam">colleagues</a>. While I
think that he also showed me a publicly available description of such a setup
at the time, I can now no longer find it.  Therefore I decided to reproduce the
necessary steps and document them here as a reminder for myself and others that
may find this information useful. Most of it is based on an excellent guide on
the <a href="http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Metasploit_Postgres_Setup">FedoraProject Wiki</a> that describes
how to get Metasploit to run with a systemwide PostgreSQL installation on
Fedora.</p>

<p>The first step is to initialise the PostgreSQL database. Pick a target
directory (<code>~/.postgresql</code> in my case) and run:
```
someone@lolcathost:~$ initdb &mdash;pgdata=${HOME}/.postgresql
The files belonging to this database system will be owned by user &ldquo;someone&rdquo;.
This user must also own the server process.</p>

<p>[&hellip;]</p>

<p>Data page checksums are disabled.</p>

<p>fixing permissions on existing directory /home/someone/.postgresql &hellip; ok
creating subdirectories &hellip; ok
selecting default max_connections &hellip; 100
selecting default shared_buffers &hellip; 128MB
creating configuration files &hellip; ok
creating template1 database in /home/someone/.postgresql/base/1 &hellip; ok</p>

<p>[&hellip;]</p>

<p>WARNING: enabling &ldquo;trust&rdquo; authentication for local connections
You can change this by editing pg_hba.conf or using the option -A, or
&mdash;auth-local and &mdash;auth-host, the next time you run initdb.</p>

<p>Success. You can now start the database server using:</p>

<pre><code>postgres -D /home/someone/.postgresql
</code></pre>

<p>or</p>

<pre><code>pg_ctl -D /home/someone/.postgresql -l logfile start
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p>Next, start the database server:
<code>
someone@lolcathost:~$ postgres -D ${HOME}/.postgresql -k ${HOME}/.postgresql
LOG:  database system was shut down at 2013-10-04 08:56:33 CEST
LOG:  autovacuum launcher started
LOG:  database system is ready to accept connections
</code>
You can now create a PostgreSQL user account for Metasploit to use:
<code>
someone@lolcathost:~$ createuser -h ${HOME}/.postgresql -P msf_user
Enter password for new role:
Enter it again:
</code></p>

<p>Next, a database must be created:</p>

<p><code>
someone@lolcathost:~$ createdb -h ${HOME}/.postgresql --owner=msf_user msf_database
</code></p>

<p>Finally, create a database configuration file for Metasploit. It seems that
<code>~/.msf4/database.yml</code> is automatically used by Metasploit to establish a
database connection:</p>

<p>```
someone@lolcathost:~/repos/metasploit-framework$ cat > ~/.msf4/database.yml &lt;&lt;EOF</p>

<blockquote><p>production:</p>

<pre><code>adapter: postgresql
database: msf_database
username: msf_user
password: &lt;your password&gt; 
host: /home/someone/.postgresql
pool: 75
timeout: 5
</code></pre>

<p>EOF
```</p></blockquote>

<p>Finally, start Metasploit and enjoy database support. Should you stop the
database server, or reboot your system, just remember to start PostgreSQL as
shown above before you start Metasploit and you&rsquo;re good to go again.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
